拉斯·冯·提尔
《女性瘾者》
斯塔茜·马汀（青年Joe）
你如何看待Joe？
我…
I...
我会说…她…
would say... I mean she...
电影中她的前后变化很大
Throughout the film she evolves a lot. So...
我饰演的是回叙的时期
The part I took were all the flashbacks...
和夏洛特那个时期很不同
...were very different to the part that Charlotte had done.
我们没怎么讨论过Joe这个人物和形象
And we haven't really talked about who Joe is or how she is.
因为 我觉得
Because... I mean in my mind I've...
要知道 人在15岁时 和三四十岁时不可能是一样的
You know... You were never the same when you were 15 or you were 30 and 40, so...
要一直扮演同一个角色很困难
It's difficult to play the same character all the time.
有趣的是
So that was really interesting....
我不需要去多想 夏洛特对Joe的看法
...to not have to think of much in... what Charlotte thought Joe was...
因为我觉得 她还处于探索的时期
cause in my mind she was still discovering a lot of things, and...
她在习得她自己的想法
She was learning what she believed in...
她自己认为的对和错
and what she thought was right, and what she thought was wrong...
形成她自己的一种…
and having her own sort of...
行为准则
...code of etiquette.
这是我对她的感觉
That's my experience I had with her.
她逐渐变得
And she became much more...
果断和坚强多了
decisive and strong than who she was...
后来和Jerome 有了Marcel的时候
...later on and with Jerome... and Marcel.
然后换成夏洛特 但已经是另一个Joe了
And then, it switches to Charlotte. But that's a different Joe.
Joe是何时得知她的性瘾的？
我认为她对性非常好奇
I think she's very curious about her sexuality.
因为她很小就知道那不寻常
Because she knows that is something very young.
知道那对她很重要
She knows that is something important to her.
但还不知道有多重要
But she doesn't quite know how important it is and...
以及怎样重视它
how to honor that importance.
她通过火车上的经历才发现
She discovers it through be on the train and...
经过这些事她变得
All these experience she becomes...
更确信了
more sure...
她发展出这么一种
So she develops this sort of...
一种…
a kind of...
强硬的 主张
hardcore opinions about...
她会为了想要的不顾一切
She's gonna go this far to get what she wants.
她很固执 就是这个词
She's very opinionated. That's it.
我仍…
I still...
时而感到看不透她
have moments when I don't really know who she is.
因为像是种无止境的发现
Because it's sort of a never ending discovery.
拍戏时…
Be on set and...
会…突然…
Be on set and... It would... come and I...
某个场景突然间让你觉得
You be in a scene and it would hit me and I'm like...
啊原来她是这种感觉 她是这样的人
Uh this is how she feels. This is who she is.
很有意思
Really interesting.
Joe和Jerome之间是什么关系？
Jerome的关系…
Her relationship with Jerome...
他有点像 一种…
Sort of he's... just is a sort of...
实用品 起初时
...utility at first.
他是她获取所需的途径
He is a way of getting what she wants.
这样是种办法
And it's a solution.
后来他成了她的上司
And he later becomes her boss.
结果他们在一起了 我觉得
They end up having relationship together which I think...
她希望能行得通
she hopes will work...
但在心底知道
but deep down knows that...
不会的
it's not.
因为欲望太强烈了
Because she's so driven.
但她努力了
But she tries.
尽管她是爱他的
Even though she loves him....
自始至终
...throughout the movie.
这不会阻止她
It's not gonna deter her from...
去外面 约会其他人
having relationships with other people, and going out...
挺矛盾的 因为没那么容易抉择
It's a difficult one cause it's not so obvious.
因为她是在反对自己 反对爱情
Cause she goes against her. And she's against love.
因此这段关系挺有趣的
So that relationship's quite interesting.
起初有段时间发展得不错
And it develops well through time at first.
第一次遇见那时他们只有…
When they'd meet originally they just sort of...
性…
...have sex and...
她没对他多想
...she doesn't really think much of him.
但后来事情变了 他成了…
But then it escalates and he becomes...
她的一种迷恋
...this obessesion, this sort of...
她想去拥有 抚摸 感受的一个男人
...man that she wants to possess and touch and feel and...
然后她得到了
And she gets it.
但不知何故 这还是不够
And then somehow it's not enough.
你饰演了15年间的Joe
她有何变化？
她确实有点…
She does sort of...
想要作为一员融入进
wanting to be part of a group and wanting to be...
某个志同道合的集体
part of something that they all believe in collectively.
随后她意识到
And then she realized it's...
自己的欲望比其他女孩强烈 因此而脱离
Her drive is stronger than the other girls' and become separated from that.
由此她成长了
Through that she grows up.
更加独立 注重自己的需求和欲望
Much more individual, and much more focused on her needs and her wants.
彻底将自己孤立于集体和人群之外
And completely dissociate herself from groups and people.
她终于
And she ends up...
几乎以自我为荣
almost proud of who she is and...
她不会以性欲为耻
She's not gonna be ashamed of wanting to have sex.
这对她是件幸事
And it's a celebration for her.
是种新发现
It's sort of discovery.
你对冯提尔的执导怎么看？
我发现拉斯的一件事是
One of the things I realized with Lars is that...
所有和他合作过的演员 我认为
all the actors he's worked with, I think...
他相信他们会为角色带来相符的东西 与他所想是一致的
He knows they would bring something in line with the characters, in line with what he wants to see.
因此给他们自由去发挥
And so he just gives them freedom to do that.
而不是好像…
...rather than kind of...
在角色周围画地为牢
putting a cage down a character and...
只准演员在里面活动
letting the actor only pace on that cage...
而且他很有耐心
And he's very patient.
我觉得他很严格 以他那种自由的方式
He's very precise, in his sort of freedom style, I think.
因为他…
Cause he...
他会一直等到最最精确的那一点
He won't stop until he has that exact millisecond.
但他不会告诉你怎样到达那一点
But he won't tell you how to get to the millisecond.
得靠你自己去发现
It's sort of you to discover that.
看到那些性爱场面是什么感觉？
现在的特效水平真是不可思议 因为…
It's absolutely incredible what you can do now with special effects, because...
我当然清楚自己没有做爱
I clearly know I didn't have sex.
但是看起来就和真的一样
But it bloody looks like I am.
连我自己都相信了
And it's all convinced me so...
真是不可思议
It's just incredible.
拍戏时你们与床戏替身是如何合作的？
我们…
We would...
有时是先拍完
...sometimes do the scenes before.
然后再用床戏替身拍一遍
And then they will film it with the porn doubles.
或是
Or...
先用替身来拍
They would shoot it with the porn doubles.
因为他们需要看看哪个姿势镜头最好
Because they needed to see which position worked best for the camera.
这些最好用替身来做因为他们…
Which is best to do with porn doubles because they just...
不像我这般顾虑
...don't care as much as I would do.
然后我得去复制那个姿势
And then I would have to go and then copy the position.
技术性得不行
And it was incredibly technical...
有人觉得 但你会性奋起来的吧
People like "But you're gonna get aroused..."
我想说 才不会 这是我见过最性奋不起来的场面了
I'm like "No. It's the least arousing situation I've EVER been in."
因为有人在叫你动动小拇指
Because someone's telling you to move your tiny finger...
再高一英寸 因为那就是刚才的位置
An inch higher because that's where the girl had it...
全身贴满了小点
You've got all these dots on your body.
太机械 太技术性了
It's so mechanical and technical.
You almost forget that I gonna supe impressive things.
你都要忘了自己是来给大片跑龙套的了
因为你会想说 这样真的就行吗
Cause you want to say, "Is this really gonna work?"
就是皮肤上一堆黑点而已
It's just black dots on my skin...
然后摆个姿势
...and a position.
但是确实怎样做到了
But somehow it does work.
全靠他们
Hands off to them.
冯提尔是怎样导演性爱场面的？
他想要拍得粗俗
He wants it to be ugly.
想要拍得真实
He wants it to be real, because...
因为这才是真实的样子 不是吗
That's what it really is, isn't it?
每天晚上的样子
At the end of the day.
可能粗俗 可能…
It can be ugly and it can be quite...
原始
...raw.
效果很好
It works well, because...
因为是拉斯 他有种特殊的风格
It's Lars and he has that peculiar style...
这个很难回答
It's a tricky one.
我觉得 就是因为他拍得如此真实才正对了
But he, I think, by making it so real, it completely works.
拍得挺粗俗
Making it quite ugly and...
有点青筋毕现那种
kinda veiny your face I think it's...
这是件好事 因为这样才没成为一部色情片
It's a good thing, because it doesn't become a porn movie.
我觉得 就是这一点会使人们感到惊讶
I think that's what people might be quite shocked about.
就是这并非一部色情片
It's that it's not a porn movie.
我不知道有谁看了会性奋 我是没有
I dunno who watched it and who got aroused. I didn't.
我不看色情片 所以我不知道
I don't watch porn, so I don't know...
拍摄期间最怪的事是什么？
怪的是 你才刚拍完 转眼这就变成了一个色情片现场
It's weird that you shoot a scene and it suddenly becomes a porn set.
整个气氛都变了
And the whole vibe of the thing changes.
我没去过色情片现场
I've never been on porn sets...
但突然间你就到了
And suddenly you were there.
色情片演员们正在工作
The porn actors doing what they do...
才想起来可能出去一下比较好
Just realized maybe it's good to just to leave the room?
有人会说
Cause people are like "you know..."
你在演一个性瘾者
"You're playing the nymphomaniac."
你应该习惯了啊
"You should be used to it"
我想说 没有 真没有
I'm like "NO. Hell no."
我还是出去喝杯咖啡
I'm just going outside and have coffee.
留给你们去…做色情片
Let you do the whole... porn thing.
真的很奇怪 这种切换
That's quite strange. Cause it just switches.
不像…
Does not like...
简直像是滑稽戏
Does not like... It's almost like a skits of funny set.
拍拍电影 拍拍色情片
Doing a film set, doing a porno...
谈论着假体 装着假体
Talking about prosthetics, having prosthetics...
花5个钟头去
Spending 5 hours getting a...
给一个假阴道做胶粘
...fake virgina glue done...
很有意思
...is pretty interesting.
而且我觉得不可能再次发生了
And I don't think that's ever gonna happen again.
拉斯·冯·提尔
《女性瘾者》